Guide to the Center for Southern Studies in the Social Sciences and the Humanities records, 1961-1969
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Center for Southern Studies in the Social Sciences and the Humanities records 1961-1969
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. Center for Southern Studies in the Social Sciences and Humanities.
1.0 Linear Feet 1,000 Items
The Center for Southern Studies in the Social Sciences and the Humanities was an interdisciplinary center established in 1965 in order to help "organize and systematize existing scholarly interest" in Southern Studies at Duke and elsewhere. Past chairs include Edgar T. Thompson and Thomas H. Naylor. The Center folded in the late 1970s.
Collection contains materials pertaining to operation and activities of the Center for Southern Studies in the Social Studies and the Humanities including correspondence, minutes, manuscripts, printed matter, clippings, and other materials. Materials range in date from 1961-1969, with the bulk dates of 1965-1967.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Center for Southern Studies in the Social Sciences and the Humanities records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1974, 1990.
Historical Note
The Center for Southern Studies in the Social Sciences and the Humanities was an interdisciplinary center established in 1965 in order to help "organize and systematize existing scholarly interest" in Southern Studies at Duke and elsewhere. Past chairs include Edgar T. Thompson and Thomas H. Naylor. The Center folded in the late 1970s.
Collection Overview
Collection contains materials pertaining to operation and activities of the Center for Southern Studies in the Social Studies and the Humanities including correspondence, minutes, manuscripts, printed matter, clippings, and other materials, with the bulk dates of 1965-1967. In 1966, the Center sponsored an inaugural symposium, “The Changing South: An Agenda for Research.” Approximately half of the material present consists of correspondence and copies of the papers that were presented at the symposium. Materials range in date from 1961-1969, with the bulk dates of 1965-1967.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Center for Southern Studies in the Social Sciences and the Humanities.
Thompson, Edgar Tristram, 1900-.
Related Material
Edgar Tristram Thompson Papers, 1915-1985.
University Archives, Duke University.
Robert S. Rankin Papers, 1898-1977 (bulk 1927-1976).
University Archives, Duke University.
Terry Sanford Records and Papers, 1945-1998.
University Archives, Duke University.
Douglas M. Knight Records, 1949-1970.
University Archives, Duke University.
Richard L. Watson Papers, 1941-1989.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 2 Boxes
  - Board of Advisors, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Brochures and Clippings
  - Committee members and minutes, 1964-1967
  - Correspondence, various, 1964-1967
  - Faculty with interests in Southern Studies
  - Fellowship/Grant materials (2 folders), 1964-1967
  - Mailing Lists, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Symposium Speakers/Papers Presented, A-C
  - Symposium Speakers/Papers Presented, H-L
  - Symposium Speakers/Papers Presented, M-P
  - Symposium Speakers/Papers Presented, R-Th
  - Symposium Speakers/Papers Presented, Ti-V